Now let's look at the last situation in this lesson the last one we're going to talk about and it is
现在让我们看一下本课中最后一个我们要讨论的情况，它是
quite a common one.
很常见的一个。
So we'll dive into two different expressions for it.
因此，我们将深入研究两种不同的表达方式。
OK.
好的。
Two people are in a car.
车上有两个人。
One is the driver.
一是司机。
The other is the passenger in the front seat.
另一个是前排乘客。
They are looking for a certain restaurant but neither are sure where it is.
他们正在寻找某家餐厅，但都不确定它在哪里。
The driver needs to focus on driving so he tells the other person to carefully watch for the place.
司机需要专注于驾驶，所以他告诉其他人要小心注意这个地方。
They want to go.
他们想去。
So maybe the restaurant lets make a name let's say the restaurant's name is Cleo's and it's we know
所以也许这家餐厅让我们起个名字让我们说餐厅的名字是 Cleo's 我们知道
it's going to be a blue a blue sign.
这将是一个蓝色的蓝色标志。
We know the sign on the restaurant is blue and we know it's called Cleo's gay.
我们知道餐厅的标志是蓝色的，而且我们知道它叫 Cleo's gay。
But I need to drive.
但我需要开车。
I can't be doing this right.
我不能正确地做这件事。
Maybe we're not using G.P.S..
也许我们没有使用 G.P.S.。
OK.
好的。
I can't look back and forth all the time so I need your help.
我不能一直来回看，所以我需要你的帮助。
That's the situation I need you to help me.
这就是我需要你帮助我的情况。
So you need to be doing this while I'm driving.
所以你需要在我开车的时候这样做。
So what can we say.
那么我们能说什么呢。
Well we can use an expression that we learned earlier in the lesson.
好吧，我们可以使用我们在本课前面学到的表达式。
The second one that we learned was to keep an eye on something we can change it slightly and use the
我们学到的第二个方法是密切关注一些我们可以稍微改变它并使用
same expression almost to say to watch for something we can say it like this.
同样的表达几乎要说要注意我们可以这样说的东西。
Hey hey keep an eye out for a blue sign that says Cleo's OK.
嘿嘿，留意一个蓝色标志，上面写着 Cleo 没事。
So that means doesn't have to be one eye.
所以这意味着不必是一只眼睛。
Right.
正确的。
But it just means to be aware of what's going on around us so that you can spot it when we're close.
但这只是意味着要了解我们周围发生的事情，以便在我们靠近时您可以发现它。
We can use this expression.
我们可以使用这个表达式。
Keep an eye out for lots of other things.
留意很多其他的事情。
It just means to be aware of what's going on around you so that you can catch something or spot something
它只是意味着要注意周围发生的事情，以便您可以捕捉到某些东西或发现某些东西
when it appears when it's there doesn't mean you actually look look look look look for it we'll just
当它出现时并不意味着你真的看起来
do what you do normally but make sure you have your awareness.
做你平时做的事，但要确保你有你的意识。
Make sure you're aware of what's going on.
确保你知道发生了什么。
So can you please keep an eye out for any opportunities job opportunities that you think would be good
所以你能留意任何你认为好的工作机会吗
for me if you hear about any opportunities please let me know.
对我来说，如果您听说有任何机会，请告诉我。
So that doesn't mean you need to look for a job for me.
所以这并不意味着你需要为我找工作。
But if you do talk to anybody who mentions that there's a job opening or an availability.
但是，如果您确实与提到有职位空缺或有空缺的人交谈。
Well maybe I would be a good fit.
好吧，也许我会很合适。
You can tell me about that.
你可以告诉我。
Keep an eye out for that.
请注意这一点。
OK.
好的。
Keep an eye out for articles about maybe this thing I'm trying to understand better maybe there's a
留意关于也许这件事的文章我想更好地理解也许有
topic that I'm trying to learn more about maybe A.I. for example keep an eye out for articles about
我试图了解更多关于人工智能的主题。例如，留意关于
A.I. research and if you find any send them to me.
人工智能研究，如果你发现任何发送给我。
That doesn't mean you need to go and look for a bunch of articles but you need to be aware of what's
这并不意味着你需要去寻找一堆文章，但你需要知道什么是
going on around you so that if you do find any as you're browsing on the internet then you can send
在您周围进行，因此如果您在互联网上浏览时确实找到了任何内容，那么您可以发送
them to me.
他们给我。
Keep an eye out for that.
请注意这一点。
So it's really useful.
所以它真的很有用。
It's really useful because it's very versatile because it can be used in so many different ways.
它非常有用，因为它非常通用，因为它可以以多种不同的方式使用。
OK but there's another one that we use for the car situation which is not so flexible which can not
好的，但是还有另一种我们用于汽车情况的方法，它不太灵活，不能
be used in as General away.
被用作一般远。
And that is and that is keep your eyes peeled.
那就是，那就是睁大眼睛。
Keep your eyes peeled for a blue sign that says Cleo's that one is generally only for things that we're
密切注意一个蓝色标志，上面写着 Cleo 的那个通常只适用于我们的东西
looking at with the articles with the job opportunities.
看与 th 的文章e 工作机会。
That's not something that we necessarily see we could hear about it.
这不是我们必须看到我们可以听到的东西。
We could just know about it.
我们只能知道它。
We can find out about it in any way.
我们可以通过任何方式了解它。
So it's not only about your eye seeing something but keep your eyes peeled for something usually is
因此，这不仅关乎你的眼睛看到的东西，而且让你的眼睛保持警惕，通常是
only your eyes.
只有你的眼睛。
Keep your eyes peeled for a sign that says Cleo's it's blue.
睁大你的眼睛去寻找一个标志，上面写着 Cleo 是蓝色的。
OK.
好的。
I will I will I will keep your eyes peeled for the shore.
我会的 我会的 我会让你的眼睛盯着岸边。
We're out on a boat OK.
我们出去坐船了。
And we're trying to get back before the storm comes.
我们正试图在暴风雨来临之前回来。
Keep your eyes peeled for the shoreline.
留意海岸线。
There it is.
它在那里。
I see it.
我看到了。
So keeping your eyes peeled is actually looking out for something specific.
因此，睁大眼睛实际上是在寻找特定的东西。
You know what you're looking for.
你知道你在找什么。
You don't know exactly where it is.
你不知道它到底在哪里。
So that's the difference between them.
所以这就是他们之间的区别。
Keep an eye out for is much more general and very useful.
留意它更通用且非常有用。
The expressions that we talked about in this lesson are all really common and so are the situations
我们在这节课中谈到的表达方式都很常见，情况也很常见
that we learn them in.
我们学习它们。
I hope you found this lesson both useful and interesting.
我希望你觉得这节课既有用又有趣。
So what I'd like you to do to practice is to try to write two examples for each of the expressions that
所以我想让你练习的是尝试为每个表达式写两个例子
we learned more generally.
我们学到了更普遍的东西。
I'd like you to try to use them when you find yourself in similar situations to the situations we talked
当您发现自己处于与我们讨论的情况相似的情况时，我希望您尝试使用它们
about in this lesson.
关于本课。
One thing that it's very important to keep in mind is that situations offer the context within which
需要牢记的一件非常重要的事情是，情境提供了情境
we can really understand what an Russian means if you just learn the expression it's really hard to
我们真的可以理解俄语的意思，如果你只是学会了这很难理解的表达方式
get the actual meaning and it's very hard to actually use it naturally.
得到实际含义，很难自然地实际使用它。
But when you learn it in a situation in context that becomes much easier you understand.
但是，当您在上下文中学习它时，您会更容易理解。
Oh this works here but not there.
哦，这在这里有效，但在那里无效。
And I hope I've made in this lesson I hope I've made those those distinctions clear.
我希望我在这一课中已经阐明了这些区别。
So when you're watching movies when you're having conversations with others when you're reading whatever
所以当你看电影时当你和别人交谈时当你阅读任何东西时
pay very careful attention to not only the new expressions the new words pay very close attention to
不仅要非常注意新的表达方式 新词要非常注意
the context because context can give you the usage and that is actually really important.
上下文，因为上下文可以为您提供用法，这实际上非常重要。
Just because something means this doesn't necessarily mean you should use it all the time.
仅仅因为某事意味着这并不一定意味着您应该一直使用它。
You have to know when people usually use it.
您必须知道人们通常何时使用它。
OK.
好的。
So practice this and I'll see you in the next lesson.
所以练习这个，我们下节课见。